http://www.aza.org/privacy-policy

FrogWatch USA
Black-footed Ferret Recovery and Reintroduction Program Analysis
Federal Agencies and Public Comments
Take Action!
YouTube
Enter your search query in the field below. Click the X to close.
Home Privacy Policy
We are committed to protecting your privacy and maintaining the security of your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by AZA including through the URL http://www.AZA.org, as well as http://network.aza.org/home (hereafter the "Site"), www.wildlifetraffickingalliance.org, and the TailsUp! mobile gaming app. By accessing the site or the Connect magazine or TailsUp! mobile gaming apps, you agree to what personal information we collect from you, how we collect it, what we do with it, and who we share your data with, including how we share information with advertisers and third parties, as set forth in this Privacy Policy.
HOW TO CONTACT US
Our postal address is: 8403 Colesville Rd, Ste. 710, Silver Spring, MD 20910
We can be reached via e-mail at generalinquiry@aza.org or you can reach us by telephone at 301-562-0777.
This Site is owned and operated by AZA for the benefit of its members and other visitors interested in zoos and aquariums. Our headquarters is located at 8403 Colesville Road, Suite 710, Silver Spring, Maryland 20910-3314. AZA reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy, without further notice.
UPDATES
You should review this Privacy Policy. By continuing to access or use the Site, you agree to be bound by then-current terms of the Privacy Policy. Please consult our Terms of Use for additional conditions that apply to your use of, and access to, the Site.
INFORMATION YOU VOLUNTARILY PROVIDE
You may provide us with certain information about yourself in an application for membership or renewal, a request for information, a personal donation or payment for goods or services, a response to surveys, event registrations, participation in our FrogWatch USA citizen science program (“FrogWatch USA”) or any similar program sponsored by us. In addition, your personal information is received by us when you forward a web page, electronic postcard, electronic ballot, or electronic newsletter.
AZA collects and maintains certain portions of this personal information. A Member’s personal data (particularly contact information) will be maintained (and available to the Member for rectification upon request) during the duration of an AZA membership in any category, and for EU residents only this lapsed member information will be destroyed approximately four years after membership ceases.  AZA will keep information about your “opt out” of particular communications, for the AZA business purpose so that your instructions are implemented.  AZA will keep financial records of any payments (including credit card information) of yours for AZA business purposes until no longer required for accounting, tax or similar purposes. Subject to our routine destruction policy, we may also retain for no more than four years any e-mail addresses of you and those to whom you may forward AZA electronic content and any other information collected in the forms you create.
INFORMATION WE GATHER AUTOMATICALLY
We also use certain standard Internet technologies to collect other information that cannot identify you personally when you visit our website. This non-personally identifiable information may include your IP address, the type of browser you are using, the type of operating system you are using and the domain name of your Internet service provider. AZA logs non-personally identifiable information, and aggregates it for system administration and to monitor the use of our Site. We use the aggregated information to measure the number of visits to our Site, the average time spent on our Site, the number of pages viewed, and various other Site statistics. This monitoring helps us to provide a more useful and engaging online experience to AZA.org visitors, and helps us to improve the quality of our content.
AZA uses cookies, tokens, and from time to time may use other tracking technologies in order to make the results available for your on-site searches. Token-based authentication is a security technique that authenticates the users who attempt to log in to a server, a network, or some other secure system, using a security token provided by the server.  Tokens are used in the login process to the Members Only section of the Site. The token controls the login process expire after 24 hours, unless you use "Member log out", which removes the cookie immediately. The AZA Network uses a cookie, which is a small file that is sent out by a website, accepted by the user's browser, and placed on the user's hard drive. You can always set your browser to warn of cookies being placed, and then chose which cookies you want to accept, or you can set your browser to reject all cookies. AZA does not match any information gathered by cookies or tokens with personal information you may have voluntarily submitted to AZA.
AZA may use third-party network advertising companies to serve ads on the Site. Such third-party advertising companies may set up and access cookies or tokens on your browser in order to serve these ads and they may use cookies and other technology to collect information about your online activities on this and other websites. However, AZA will not provide your personal information to any of these companies, except as may be otherwise permitted by you or this Privacy Policy.
The AZA websites use Google Analytics,  a service that transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. The data that AZA receives from Google Analytics does not identify individual users. AZA uses reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.  Users have the choice to opt-out of Google Analytics and Advertising cookies altogether at Google Analytics Opt-Out Add-on.
Also, AZA and third-party vendors including Google use first-party cookies (the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (for example, the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on past visits to our website. More specifically, the AZA website has implemented and uses display advertising, and AZA uses Google Analytics to improve user experience and implement marketing strategies. If you would like to opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, you may use the Ads Preference Manager at the Google website.
In any event, AZA will not match your personally identifiable data in our possession with the aggregate non-identifiable data from Google Analytics. Nor will AZA share your personally identifiable data with Google or Google Analytics.  AZA complies with all applicable laws and regulations that protect your privacy.
USE OF INFORMATION
We may use the information you voluntarily provide to contact you regarding your AZA membership, zoo and aquarium information that may be of interest to you, AZA programs, and to invite you to support our programs. We may also send such information to the people whose e-mail addresses you provide when forwarding AZA electronic content. When we do so, our sole business intent is to serve and enlarge our community of informed zoo and aquarium supporters. You can quickly and easily "opt out" of future such communications by following the instructions on any electronic communication we send.
From time to time, except for EU residents, we may make such voluntary information, excluding credit card information (which will never be disclosed), available to AZA affiliate organizations or to sponsors or licensees that provide special programs or services that we think you might find of interest. AZA uses strict diligence in determining which reputable companies become AZA sponsors and licensees, to assure that such organizations are committed to protecting your privacy.
USER POSTINGS AND CONTENT
Some sections of the Site allow you as a user to provide or post content, messages, screen names, computer files and other materials. Any such information you choose to post, including any of your personally identifiable information, AZA will consider to be public information and not subject to the limitations contained in this Privacy Policy.
In addition, we use frog and toad observations you may provide in connection with FrogWatch USA. A primary goal of FrogWatch USA is to maintain a universally accessible, centralized database of frog and toad observations. To this end, we have partnered with the National Geographic Society (NGS) under a National Science Foundation (NSF) grant to develop, implement and evaluate a web-based software platform called Fieldscope (www.fieldscope.org) for the purpose of enabling FrogWatch USA volunteers to enter, view, manipulate and analyze their data. AZA will have access to information that you submit through the Fieldscope website in connection with FrogWatch USA. All data you may provide, such as details of an observation and its associated location (species, numbers, etc.), to AZA in connection with FrogWatch USA, through the Fieldscope website or otherwise, will be made available to all users registered with FrogWatch USA, NGS, NSF, scientists, and others who are interested in examining the distribution, abundance, and trends of North American frog and toad species. However, only information pertaining to frog and toad observations is available to FrogWatch USA users; no personal contact information is ever made public.
The Fieldscope website is owned and operated by the National Geographic Society and subject to its privacy policy posted thereon.
For more information regarding AZA’s rights to data provided to it in connection with FrogWatch USA, please read the Terms of Use on our website.
YOUR CHOICE
If you wish to update or remove your personal information, or if you do not wish your personal information to be shared with affiliated third parties, please e-mail us at generalinquiry@aza.org.
AZA allows donors to contribute through mobile texts. Donors who contribute in this manner have the option of instructing AZA that they would prefer to "opt out" (a) of the sharing of their contact information with third parties AZA determines may have offers or services of interest to donors or (b) of receiving further communications from AZA itself (which also would prevent the sharing of contact information with third parties). Mobile donors may exercise their "opt out" choices by clicking here. For EU residents, they can choose to “opt-in” to share the personal data in (a) or (b) above by email to generalinquiry@aza.org
OTHER
AZA links to other websites not affiliated with AZA. AZA attempts to link only to those websites which also respect your privacy. However, AZA’s Privacy Policy does not apply to your interactions with other websites and AZA is not responsible for the content or privacy policies of third-party websites. Please check with these third-party websites for their specific privacy policies at generalinquiry@aza.org.
For more information regarding linking to the AZA website, please read the Terms of Use on our website.
SECURITY
AZA uses generally accepted, industry-standard security systems, software, and encryption technologies to protect against unauthorized access to AZA servers, equipment, and other components. This includes using industry-standard security systems to protect credit card processing information. Although AZA takes reasonable precautions to prevent or at least minimize unauthorized access of your information, the current state of technology cannot allow and AZA does not warrant or guarantee that personally identifiable information will never be illegally accessed, used, or disclosed.
CHILDREN'S GUIDELINES
AZA does not knowingly collect identifiable personal information from children under age 13. Nor will AZA collect personal data from EU residents under the age of 16 without the express written consent of a parent. If we discover that a person under these ages has violated either of these policies and provided us with any personally identifiable information, we will delete that information from our systems. We are unable to reply to information requests from children under the age of 13, if so identified. A parent or guardian must initiate any requests for information from children under the age of 13 on their behalf. We encourage parents to supervise children when they browse the Internet.
NOTICE TO EU RESIDENTS
EU residents have specific privacy rights. These include:
Your right to access your personal data,
Your right to rectify inaccurate or incomplete personal data, including the right to erase on request,
Your right to restrict or suspend the processing of your personal data,
Your right to complain to AZA and appropriate EU authorities,
Your right to be informed,
Your right to data portability, where you can receive personal data you have provided and ask it be transferred to another in a safe and secure way,
Your right to object to decisions based on automated processing,
Your right to withdraw your consent at any time.
In this Section
Terms of Use
Privacy Policy
Photo Credits
Partners
Advertise
Sitemap
Related Information
I Accept
This site uses cookies to offer you a better browsing experience. If you continue using our website, we'll assume that you are happy to receive all cookies on this website and you agree to our Privacy Policy.
Find a Zoo or Aquarium
Donate to AZA
Contact Us
Member Login
Search the site
Find a member
Donate to AZA
Contact Us
